### **PROFILE**

Accomplished technology entrepreneur and leader with extensive experience creating innovative best-in-class products, breakthrough technologies, and successful companies. Demonstrated successes in high-profile venture-funded startups and established public companies by creating disruptive innovations and converting them into high-growth businesses. Core competencies include:

- Business Incubation
- Strategic Vision & Execution
- Business & Financial Modeling
- Market Trends & Insights
- Product Innovation
- Partnerships & Alliances
- Thought Leadership
- New Business Development
- Business Strategy & Planning
- Team Mentorship & Advisory
- Competitive Analysis
- M&A / Business Due-diligence

## **HIGH IMPACT RESULTS**

Created and led several new business initiatives in the areas such as Cybersecurity, Cloud-based Productivity Services for SMB, SalesTech, HealthTech, and FinTech., which collectively became the foundation for new businesses at Fuji Xerox, generating \$500+M of revenue. Formulated investment theses, incubated new business concepts leveraging disruptive technologies, validated through customer pilots, developed business cases, and established strategic partnerships with innovative startups to accelerate new business creation.

**Founded, built, sold, and transitioned 150+ people Internet software company, NexPrise.** Raised several rounds of investment from well-known VCs, produced a successful industry-leading enterprise SaaS and acquired a blue-chip customer base of 40+ Global 2000 companies generating an annual revenue of \$20+M.

Won several extremely competitive research grants exceeding \$30M for Lockheed Martin's AIC from DARPA, a high-profile national advanced research agency. Created an exciting vision, assembled a nationally recognized technology team that invented path-breaking technologies, and established the Artificial Intelligence Center (AIC) as a "Center of Excellence" for enterprise integration and e-business technologies.

Transformed a 100+ person business unit at Fuji Xerox that led to revenue growth of 250% (\$25M). Architected a new product strategy & roadmap that delivered SaaS applications for IT management targeting the SMB market.

Increased revenue of SuppplySolution, a SaaS company, by 30% and reduced expenses by 25%, which led to the company's successful sale. Crafted a turnaround business plan, including a new product strategy and resource plan that led to profitability and revenue growth.

## **EXPERIENCE**

FX Palo Alto Research Laboratory (Subsidiary of FUJI XEROX (FX), \$10B Revenue)

2011-Present

Palo Alto, California

Develops advanced technologies, products, and new ventures.

## Vice President, Business Innovation & New Business Development

Recruited by the CEO to develop new products/services and business strategies that transform FX into a technology-enabled services company, primarily through new business ventures.

- Founded, organized, and led a Business Innovation division (**sponsored by FX President**), whose mission is to discover, validate, incubate, and launch new innovative businesses that leverage disruptive technologies.
- Created, led, and evangelized several new business initiatives, resulting in the formation of strategic business units that generated \$500+M in cumulative revenue.
- Developed and launched a data analytics service (Sales Motivator) through a global software partner, which achieved over 100K paid users at 18K companies to generate recurring annual revenue of \$10+ Million.

- Instrumental in launching a business unit that provides a suite of cloud-based SaaS applications for mid-market customers in Japan. The business unit acquired a new customer base numbering 350+ in 5 years.
- Acquired several US patents for applications of emerging technologies such as AI, Blockchain, IoT, etc.

# **Product Strategy & New Business Development Consultant (multiple companies)**

2005 - 2011

Recruited by CEOs and senior executives of various companies to develop new business concepts, strategies & plans that drove new high-growth products/services.

- Transformed a 100+ person business unit through new product positioning & roadmap and delivered on-demand software service for IT management for the SMB market, resulting in revenue growth of 250% (\$25M).
- Incubated next-generation content management service that includes contextual search, BPM, and information discovery technologies that led to the launch of a novel cloud service business generating \$20M revenue.
- Developed product strategy, roadmap, and GTM plan for SummitLogic startup, resulting in sales contracts of \$1+M from several large automotive companies in one year.
- Served on the boards of venture & angel funded startup companies.

## SUPPLYSOLUTION, INC., \$ 20M Revenue

2003 - 2005

Pleasanton, California

Business e-commerce SaaS company that connected large manufacturers and 3500+ small suppliers.

# Senior Vice President, Product Management, Marketing, & Business Development

Recruited by the CEO to provide strategic and day-to-day leadership to turnaround and sell the unprofitable company of 100+ people.

- Developed new product vision, business strategy, and business plan; and raised \$6+M additional investment.
- Crafted business strategy, including product and resource plan that reduced expenses by 25% and increased revenue by 30%.
- Created product positioning, roadmap, and value proposition that increased critical customer retention by 100%
- Partnered with the CEO to prepare the company for sale to Tradebeam Holdings/Carlyle Ventures at 3X revenue and successfully transitioned the company.

# BAY PARTNERS, \$1B under management

2002 - 2003

Cupertino, California

Early-stage venture capital firm with 200 portfolio companies, including Brocade, Sonic Wall, Informatica, and BEA.

#### **Executive-In-Residence**

Recruited to incubate new ventures and advance current portfolio companies.

- Created many new investment ideas and incubated a new venture.
- Directed investment due diligence and provided executive-level operational assistance to portfolio companies.
- Sourced many deals for the firm through close connections with entrepreneurs.

#### **NEXPRISE, INC., \$20+M Revenue**

1997 - 2002

Santa Clara, California

Cloud-based strategic sourcing software to manage critical business processes between suppliers and manufacturers.

#### Founder, President & CEO

Founded, built, sold, and transitioned a successful 150 people Strategic Sourcing SaaS company with a well-known, best-in-class product.

- Raised \$25M through three rounds of venture financing with \$20M oversubscribed. Attracted Crosspoint, APEX, Deutsche Bank, and AVI Capital as investors.
- Recruited and led engineering, product management, & marketing team to deliver a superior product, recognized as a category leader by several F500 customers and the auto industry's major consortium of 50+ Global 1000 companies.
- Drove strategic sales initiatives that acquired a blue-chip customer base of 40+ Global 2000 companies.
- Established a charter partner program with Boeing, Ford, United Technologies, Lockheed, and GM, leading to repeat multi-million dollar deals.
- Established successful partnerships and channels with EDS, CGE&Y, PWC, and Sun Microsystems.
- Led the M&A team and completed the successful sale of NexPrise to Ventro, a public company, for 3X revenue in late 2001.

# ADVANCED TECHNOLOGY CENTER (ATC), \$150M REVENUE (DIVISION OF LOCKHEED MARTIN) 1989 – 1997 Palo Alto, California

Develops leading-edge software technologies. AIC is known for company spin-offs such as Tallarian, Redpepper, Netsys, and Dialog. AIC is a division of Lockheed Martin's Advanced Technology Center.

# **Director, Artificial Intelligence Center (AIC)**

Recruited by Vice President to develop & commercialize market-relevant technologies and products. Managed 60+ software engineers & computer scientists with a \$12 million annual budget.

- Defined strategic direction and executed a multi-year business plan to deliver highly market-relevant software.
- Established AIC as a "Center of Excellence" for enterprise integration and e-business technologies.
- Developed a nationally recognized e-business technology team that attracted \$30M DARPA contract awards.
- Created innovative software solutions that delivered \$10+M cost savings to the company.
- Built strategic alliances with vendors, consortiums, and associations, including Sun Microsystems, Texas Instruments, CommerceNet, Apple, IBM, and Silicon Graphics.
- Received prestigious "Pursuit-of-Excellence" award due to groundbreaking strategy and results.

#### **EDUCATION**

M.S., Computer Science – University of Tulsa, Tulsa, Oklahoma

M.S., Mechanical Engineering – Mississippi State University, Starkville, Mississippi Received prestigious research fellowship

B.S., Mechanical Engineering – Guindy Engineering College, India (Top 10 engineering schools in India) Graduated with Honors (<5% of students receive Honors after meeting special requirements)